One of the most common ways to measure the spread
测量数据离散程度的最常见方式之一是
of our data is by looking at the Five Number Summary,
五数概括法 (Five Number Summary)
which gives us values for calculating the range and interquartile range.
五数概括法给出了计算极值和四分位差的值
The Five Number Summary consists of five values, the maximum,
五数概括法包括五个值：最大值
the minimum, the first quartile,
最小值、第 1 四分位数
the second quartile which is also the median, and the third quartile.
第 2 四分位数 (即中位数) 以及第 3 四分位数
Consider we have the following dataset.
看看下面的数据集
The first thing we need to do to calculate
要进行五数概括
the Five Number Summary is to order our values.
首先需要对数据排序
Once ordered, the minimum and the maximum values
排序后 就很容易发现
are easy to identify as the smallest and largest values.
最小值和最大值
As we calculate it in the section on measures of center,
正如在集中趋势测量部分介绍的计算方法
the median is the middle value in our dataset.
中位数是数据集的中间值
We also call this Q2 or the second quartile because
也称为 Q2 或第 2 四分位数
50% of our data or two quarters fall below this value.
因为有 50% 的数据或 2 个四分位的数小于它
The remaining two values to complete the Five Number Summary are Q1 and Q3.
要计算的剩下两个值是 Q1 和 Q3
These values can be thought of as the medians of the data on either side of Q2.
这两个值可以看做 Q2 两侧的中位数
That is the median of these data points is Q1,
即这些数据点的中位数是 Q1
this value is such that 25% of our data fall below it,
该值使 25% 的数据小于它
and the median of these data points is Q3 or the third quartile.
这些数据点的中位数是 Q3 即第 3 四分位数
This value is such that 75% of our data fall below this mark.
该值使 75% 的数据小于这个标记
Notice, Q2 was not an either a set of these points used to calculate Q1 or Q3.
注意 Q2 不在用来计算 Q1 或 Q3 的数据集中
This provides our Five Number Summary as the following.
这样就得出以下五数概括结果
Let's consider another example for in our dataset has an even set of values.
再看一个示例 该数据集有偶数个值
Again, we first need to order the values.
同样 首先需要对值排序
We can quickly identify the maximum and the minimum.
我们可以快速找到最小值和最大值
Remember, with an even number of values,
注意 对于偶数个值
the median or Q2 is given as the mean of these two values here.
中位数或 Q2 是这两个值的均值
In order to find Q1 and Q3,
为了计算 Q1 和 Q3
we divide our dataset between the two values we use to find the median.
我们用计算中位数的两个值来拆分整个数据集
This provides these two datasets.
得出这两个数据集
Finding the median of each of these will provide Q1 and Q3.
找出每个数据集的中位数将得出 Q1 和 Q3
For this dataset, Q1 will be the mean of these two values,
对于该数据集 Q1 将是这两个值的均值
and Q3, will be the mean of these two values.
Q3 将是这两个值的均值
This provides our Five Number Summary as the following.
这样就得出以下五数概括结果
Once we've calculated all the values for the Five Number Summary,
算出五数概括法的所有值后
finding the range and interquartile range is no problem.
计算极值和四分位差就很简单了
For the first dataset,
对于第一个数据集
the range is calculated as the maximum minus the minimum.
极值是最大值减去最小值
this was 10 minus 1 or 9.
是 10 - 1 = 9
And the interquartile range is calculated as Q3 minus Q1,
四分位差是 Q3 - Q1
which is 8 minus 2 or 6.
即 8 - 2 = 6